

CONTACT

- Bryanston, South Africa
- **O83 985 7316**
- mabiyonela@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/yonela-mabi-3a226112a/
- Portfolio

SKILLS

- -Exceptional writing, editing, and proofreading skills
- Strong command of the English language
- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite and Google Docs
- Time Management
- Experience in conducting research and interviews
- Ability to work independently and meet deadlines
- -Attention to detail

EDUCATION

BA (HONOURS) - JOURNALISM AND MEDIA STUDIES Rhodes University 2020 - 2021

BA - ENGLISH AND COMMUNICATION SCIENCE

IIE Varsity College 2016 - 2018

LANGUAGES

- English
- isiXhosa

YONELA MABI

WRITER | EDITOR | BDA

PERSONAL PROFILE

Holding a BA in English and Communication Science, as well as a BA with Honours in Journalism and Media Studies degree has granted me the professionalism and versatility to expand my branches into numerous projects & fields of expertise. With experience spanning various fields, including proofreading, editing, creative writing, email marketing, SDR work, account management, social media internship, and events logistics coordination, I possess a diverse skill set that I bring to every project.

WORK EXPERIENCE...

HEMPRESS HYGIENICS | 15 MAY 2023 - CURRENT BDA & Social Media Assistant (part-time) | Remote

- -Assist with Marketplace setup
- -Fill out vendor and distribution application forms
- -Email outreach & email follow-ups
- -Admin tasks
- -Store finding lead generation
- -Social Media Assistant (Instagram)
- -Blog content writing and research
- -Search for relevant events for the founder and cofounder to attend
- -Socials reports (TikTok, Instagram, LinkedIn, Twitter)
- -Find podcasts for founder to be a part of

LIVLUSH GLOBAL I 4 MAY 2023

Guest Writer | Remote

- -Writing articles that align with the brand
- -It's a non-paid freelancer portfolio platform for upcoming writers

WORK EXPERIENCE...

CLIMATE TRANSFORMED | 20 JULY 2022 - 25 APRIL 2023

Logistics Coordinator | Remote

- -Organized the arrangements for multiple virtual events, which involved managing logistics calls, scheduling, and creating speaker packs
- -Helped with carrying out marketing and promotional tasks
- -Kept meticulous records of all event-related activities.

Associate Editor | Remote

- -Checking for errors in written content and creating written material
- -Adding important event-related details to Cvent
- -Providing assistance to the Head of Content as required
- -Examining and offering suggestions on the written content of the website
- -Adding relevant information to SharePoint
- -Managing CRM.

Account Manager | Remote

- Performing SDR list-building and appointment-setting activities for larger-level sponsors and speakers (for senior management team to pitch)
- -Conducting and delivering independent research to identify potential sponsors and speakers for events
- -Executing outreach based on target
- -Managing the entire sales cycle, from prospecting through to close for sponsors on specific events
- -Grow and maintain a strong sales pipeline
- -CRM management
- -Relationship building and post-sale account management
- -Take minutes in meetings with potential speakers/sponsors and the founder
- -Schedule meetings with potential speakers/sponsors for the founder
- -Copywriting for email templates and proofreading
- -LinkedIn outreach
- -Pitching to potential speakers/sponsors via email

GROWTHONICS | 18 JAN 2021 - 18 JULY 2022

Sales Development Representative | Hybrid

- -Sent follow-up emails to convert meetings
- -Reported on activity and updated databases
- -Had a great understanding of the client's industry, market, and service offering
- -Booked meetings in clients' calendars via Calendly
- -Cold called prospects as part of the cadence
- -Created template response sheets specific to the clients
- -Identified any issues that affected the success of the clients account
- -Ensured the accounts were managed and organized correctly





WORK EXPERIENCE

THE NELSON MANDELA BAY BUSINESS CHAMBER | 9 MAY 2019 - 24 JAN 2020

Receptionist Intern | Office based

- -Attended to the switchboard
- -Took messages and forwarded them to staff concerned
- -Assisted walk-in clients with queries
- -Compiled and sent out emails
- -Assisted with COO filing when required
- -Offered office management assistance

HLUMIS'IMFUNDO ORGANISATION | APRIL 2019 - JAN 2020

Public Relations Officer | Volunteer work

- -Developed and executed PR strategies and campaigns to promote Hlumis'Imfundo
- -Managed the Facebook account
- -Conducted market research to guide PR efforts

ALGOA FM | OCTOBER 2018

Registration Assistant

Worked at the Big Walk for Cancer registration.

Duties included:

- -Sign off participant's race numbers and hand them their envelopes
- -Hand out t-shirts to the first 7000 online entrants

MEROPA COMMUNICATIONS | JUNE 2018

Social Media Intern

- -Had to get 20+ people to follow client page
- -Raised awareness of the event
- -Tweeted about the event [at least 25 tweets p/h]
- -Retweeted tweets by the client page and other colleagues

REFERENCES

Roxanne Struwig

Climate Transformed

Phone: +27 82 749 8060

McKenna Avery

Hempress Hygienics

Email: mckenna@hempresshygienics.com

Tony Kubeka

Climate Transformed

Phone: +27 60 519 1037